[
  {
    "question": "What are the two main types of film music?",
    "answer": "source music\nunderscoring"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the movie Jaws, the shark is represented by a two-note oscillating motive.",
    "answer": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "\"Running counter to the action\" is a technique that composers use to supply irony in film music.",
    "answer": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "Source music refers to music that functions as part of the drama itself, such as a character turning on a radio.",
    "answer": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "In order to associate the music with a character, John Williams utilizes - in his film music.",
    "answer": "leitmotifs"
  },
  {
    "question": "John Williams's Imperial March has also been used for -\n events between rival teams and even as a popular -",
    "answer": "sporting \nringtone"
  },
  {
    "question": "Film music always matches the mood of the action on the screen.",
    "answer": "False"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the score for the Lord of the Rings trilogy?",
    "answer": "Howard Shore"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which are true about John Williams and his career?",
    "answer": "He began composing for television in the 1950s.\nHe wrote Barack Obama's inauguration music.\nHe wrote the music for Home Alone."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which best describe the musical characteristics of the opening theme of John Williams's Imperial March from Star Wars?",
    "answer": "disjunct melody\nminor tonality\nrepeated rhythmic ostinati"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the mood of the music contradicts what is being shown on the screen, what is it called?",
    "answer": "running counter to the action"
  },
  {
    "question": "John Williams unifies his film scores using a technique also found in which?",
    "answer": "Wagner's music dramas"
  },
  {
    "question": "Underscoring in film music refers to which?",
    "answer": "music coming from an unseen source"
  },
  {
    "question": "The movie -\n is an example of a soundtrack that uses only source music.",
    "answer": "Rear Window"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following movies includes a famous scene in which the film music runs counter to the action?",
    "answer": "The Godfather"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which composer wrote the scores to the first three Harry Potter films?",
    "answer": "John Williams"
  },
  {
    "question": "The vocal music in the 2009 film Avatar is sung in which language?",
    "answer": "Na'vi"
  },
  {
    "question": "The most important function of music in film is to -",
    "answer": "set the mood"
  },
  {
    "question": "Darth Vader's theme first appeared in The Empire Strikes Back.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "question": "- is credited as having revived the grand symphonic film score.",
    "answer": "John Williams"
  }
]